（ナツキ･スバル）戻ってきたぜ
I'm back here again.
Sister, Sister. It appears
our guest is still half-asleep.
（レム）
姉様 姉様―
お客様ったら まだ寝ぼけて
いらっしゃるみたいです
Rem, Rem. For one so young,
it's quite sad how out of it he is.
（ラム）
レム レム―
お客様ったら あの年で
かわいそうにボケてるみたいだわ
What is the matter, sir?
（レム）
お客様どうかされましたか？
具合が悪いんですか？
Do you feel unwell?
What's wrong, sir?
（ラム）
お客様どうかしたの？
持病の発作でも起こした？
Do you have a chronic illness flaring up?
Let me see your hands.
（スバル）ちょっと拝借
So it's true, after all.
（スバル）
ああ… やっぱりそうだ
I wasn't mistaken.
俺は 間違ってなかった
No, sir. I think you
are mistaken about everything.
（レム）いいえ お客様―
何もかもが
間違っていると思います
No, sir. I think your
very birth was a mistake.
いいえ お客様―
きっと 生まれてきたのが
間違いだわ
When I think about what's to come,
I can't laugh off that comment.
（スバル）
のちのちのことを考えると
笑えない気がする言葉だが―
But right now, even that feels good.
今はそれも気分がいいぜ
Sister, Sister. Is our guest a troubled
man who gets off on being abused?
姉様 姉様―
お客様ったら ひょっとして
なじられて喜ぶ困ったお方？
Rem, Rem, our guest appears to be
a pervert who's turned on by insults.
レム レム―
お客さまってば どうやら
罵声を浴びて興奮する ど変態？
Sorry if that came out of nowhere,
いきなりで悪かったな
but I trust you both.
けど 俺はお前らを信じてるから
Let's be friends, okay?
仲よくやろうぜ
I heard noises, so I came to check on you.
（エミリア）
騒がしいから
見にきてみたら―
I'm glad you're all right, Subaru.
スバル 元気みたいでよかった
I had a lot on my mind a second ago,
今 さっきまで
心中複雑だったんだけど―
but seeing you blew it
all away, Emilia-tan!
エミリアたん見たら
全部吹っ飛んだよ
I guess you were the wonder
drug that my heart needed.
俺の心の特効薬は
エミリアたんだったんだね
Sorry, I have no idea what you're saying.
ごめん ちょっと
何 言ってるのか分かんない
But good morning. I'm glad you're well.
でも おはよう
無事でよかった
ああ おはよう
Yeah, good morning.
Okay, might as well get started.
んじゃ まあ 始めるとすっか
Hire me to work in this mansion!
俺を この屋敷で
雇ってくれ！
In order to survive a week in the Roswaal mansion,
I must clear two broad conditions.
（スバル）
ロズワール邸での１週間を
突破するために
必要な条件は大きく２つだ
First, I need to earn
the trust of the staff here.
１つは 屋敷関係者から
信頼を勝ち取ること
If I don't gain those two maids' favor,
彼女らのお眼鏡に
かなわない限り―
口封じで殺される
可能性が高い
odds are they'll kill me
to assure my silence.
That goes not only for Rem and Ram,
これは
レムやラムに関わらず―
but for their master, Roswaal, as well.
２人の主人である
ロズワールからのものも含める
And second, I need to defeat the shaman
attacking the Roswaal mansion...
そして ２つ目―
ロズワール邸を襲う 呪術師の―
once and for all!
撃破だ
I'm bushed!
疲れたーっ
You're quite the hard worker.
（パック）
随分と働き者だね
I'm not done yet.
（スバル）
まだまだ終わりじゃねえ
夕食の準備に 部屋掃除―
I need to prepare dinner and clean the rooms.
I'll get back to work after a little break.
ちょっと休憩したら
仕事に戻らねえと
You're so enthusiastic on your very first day.
初日から気合が入ってるね
Yeah, I guess.
そりゃ まあ―
I've got some important
things on the line here.
いろいろ 大事なものが
かかってるからなあ
By the way, what kind of
magic does Emilia-tan use?
そういえば―
エミリアたんて―
どんな魔法が使える
魔法使いなの？
Technically, she isn't a magic-user.
厳密に言うと
リアは魔法使いじゃないよ
Same goes for her contract with me.
僕との契約もそうだけど―
She uses spirit arts.
精霊使いだから
So those who use magic
and spirit arts are different?
魔法使いと精霊使いって
違うもんなんだ
Magic-users cast magic
with their own mana,
魔法使いは 自分の中の
マナを使って魔法を使う
but those who use spirit arts
draw mana from their surroundings.
逆に精霊使いは 大気中の
マナを使って術を使うんだよ
And how are those any different, Puck-sensei?
それって どんな違いに
なるわけですか？ 先生
Basically, it depends on whether you use a gate.
ずばり ゲートを用いるか
どうかだね
A gate?
（スバル）ゲート？
It's something within your body
that controls the flow of mana.
体の中にある
マナを通す門のことだよ
Through the gate, you both
draw mana in and expel it out.
ゲートを通じてマナを取り込み
ゲートを通じてマナを放出する
I see. Then it's like a tap for MP, huh?
（スバル）
なーる ＭＰ関連の蛇口のことね
You should have one too, Subaru.
スバルにもあるはずだよ
R-Really? Does that mean
even I can use magic?
えっ マジ？ ってことは
俺も魔法が使えるってこと？
Want me to figure out your attribute?
とりあえず
スバルの属性調べてみる？
Magic-users are divided into one of four attributes: fire, water, wind, and earth.
魔法には 火 水 風 土の
４つのマナ属性があるんだけど
みょんみょんみょんみょん…
Whoa, it's totally a magic sound effect!
（スバル）
おお 魔法っぽい効果音
I know what your attribute is.
（パック）
分かったよ スバルの属性
Yes! I've been waiting for this!
きた！ 待ってました
Is it the burning fire of passion?
やっぱ 情熱の火？
Or a relaxed, cool-guy water type?
それとも 冷静沈着
クールガイな水？
Or maybe a gentle wind, blowing across the plain?
あるいは 草原を吹きぬける
爽やかな風？
Or is it solid, reliable earth?
それとも どっしり
大地のように頼れる土？
Shadow
Shadow.
（パック）陰(いん)だね
（スバル）オール却下！
Shadow
None of them!?
Wow, shadow? That's very rare.
へえ 珍しい 陰属性なんて
What is shadow anyway?
（スバル）
てか 陰って何だよ
Weren't there only four attributes?
分類は４つじゃねえの？
カテゴリーエラーしてるよ？
This is a category error!
In addition to the four basic attributes,
（パック）
４つの基本属性のほかに
陰と陽って属性もあるんだよ
there's also shadow and light.
Is it actually some amazing ability?
何か 実はすごい能力なのか？
Like a talent only seen
once in five thousand years?
５千年に１度の逸材 みたいな
With shadow magic,
陰属性の魔法だと―
you can obstruct an opponent's vision, block sound,
相手の視界を塞いだり
音を遮断したり―
slow movements, and things like that.
動きを遅くしたりとかかな
It's just debuffs!?
（スバル）デバフ特化
An easy one would be something like Shamac.
簡単なのだと シャマクとかかな？
That's a blinding spell, right?
（エミリア）
確か 目くらましの魔法よね？
Want me to show you?
ちょっとやってみようか
For real? Let's see, let's see!
Wait, Puck...
（スバル）マジ？ 見せて見せて
（エミリア）ちょっとパック…
（パック）フン シャマク
Shamac!
Okay, that's it.
（パック）はい おしまい
What'd you think? That was Shamac.
（パック）
どう？ 今のがシャマクだよ
Are you all right?
（エミリア）大丈夫？
I-I'm fine!
だ… 大丈夫　地味だけど
効果はかなり強めじゃねえ？
It's not too flashy,
but it seems pretty effective!
俺もそのシャマクって魔法
使えるってことだよね？
So I can also use this Shamac, right?
Well, with the right training.
まあ 修業次第だね
Want to try the beginner's course?
体験入学してみる？
Please, Master!
お願いします 師匠！
I'll act as a support and help
use the mana inside you.
（パック）
僕が補助して スバルの中の
マナを使うから―
That way the magic will come
from your own gate.
魔法自体は
スバルのゲートから出るよ
Lia, on the off-chance that Subaru's mana goes berserk and explodes,
リアは まさかの展開で
マナが暴走して―
スバルがはじけちゃったら―
you should stand back,
so your clothes don't get all messy.
服が汚れちゃうから
離れててね
It'll only explode if I screw up really bad, right!?
ホントにありえないくらい
失敗した時だけだよね それ
If you can make relaxed, lighthearted
comments like that, you'll be fine.
軽口たたく余裕があるなら 大丈夫
Now, visualize the flow
of mana through your body.
さあ イメージしてごらん
君の体のマナの流れを
Then expel a portion of it through your gate and out of your body.
そしてその一部を ゲートから
体の外に吐き出すんだ
Visualizing, I can do.
イメージなら任せろ
妄想は得意だぜ
Fantasizing is what I do best.
みょんみょんみょんみょんみょん
Huh? That isn't good. The gate just—
あれ？ 困ったな
ちょっと急にゲート…
Long story short,
結論から言うと―
your control over your gate isn't very good,
so you shouldn't try too hard.
スバルのゲートは
制御が甘すぎるから―
無理しないほうがいいね
You're the one who said I'd be fine.
（スバル）
大丈夫って言ったのは てめえだろ
Tee-hee!
（パック）テヘヘ
That's not cute at all.
かわいくねえよ
Well, for better or worse,
your gate hasn't seen much use.
（パック）
良くも悪くも スバルのゲートは
使い込まれてないからね
That's why the mana ignored your will
and burst out like that.
だから
使う側の意思を無視して―
中身がドバッと
外に出ちゃったんだよ
What am I, a soy sauce bottle with a loose cap?
ちゃんと ふた閉めてない
しょうゆか 俺は… うっ
You shouldn't move.
動いちゃダメ
You used up all the mana in your body.
体中のマナを
出し切っちゃったんだから
Maybe you shouldn't work anymore today.
今日はもう
お仕事できないかも
No! I have to!
（スバル）それは困る！
There's no need to push yourself!
（エミリア）
無理しちゃダメだってば
This is exactly when I need to push myself.
今が無理のしどころなんだよ
I can't waste a single day.
１日だってムダにできねえ
You really are hopeless.
ホントにしかたないんだから もう
What—
（スバル）何？ ん…
Chew.
噛(か)んで
（スバル）ん？
Chew and swallow it. Ready, go!
噛んで 飲み込む　さん はい
Wh-What was that?
え… 今のって
It's a bocco fruit.
ボッコの実っていう果物
Eating it stimulates your mana,
食べると 体の中の
マナが活性化して―
allowing your gate to regain
a little of its strength.
ほんの少しだけ
ゲートが力を取り戻すの
ごめん 何か
迷惑掛けてちまって…
Sorry to make you do that for me.
You just don't get it, Subaru.
スバルは分かってないんだから
A single "thank you" is worth
more than a million "sorry"s.
ごめんって何度も言われるより―
ありがとうって
１回言ってくれたほうが―
相手は満足するの
I did it because I wanted to help,
謝ってほしいんじゃなくて―
not because I wanted an apology.
してあげたくて
したことなんだから
Okay?
So, Ram, given what you've seen so far,
（ロズワール･Ｌ･メイザース）
そーれで ラム
君から見たところ 彼の評価は
どーんなもんかな？
what do you think of him?
In terms of abilities,
he's completely incompetent,
（ラム）
能力的には
無能もいいところなのですが―
but when it counts,
he can be excessively quick-witted.
要所で目端が利きすぎる
ところがあります
I believe it may be necessary
to keep an eye on him for a time.
いくらか経過を見守る必要が
あるのではないかと
This is a problem we must
handle with utmost care.
（ロズワール）
この件は ひどーく慎重に
扱うべき問題だよ
Be sure to give the proper warnings,
くれぐれも
レムが先走らないよう―
so your sister does not act rashly.
姉の君が注意しておくよーうにね
I guess that's about all
I can expect of the first day.
（スバル）
初日は まずまずってところか
I earned quite a bit of trust
from Ram and Rem too,
レムとラムの信頼は
かなり勝ち取れた―
or so I hope.
はずだ
But the real issue is that shaman's attack.
けど問題は呪術師の襲撃か
どうやって戦えばいい
How do I fight that?
You want to know more about shamans?
（ベアトリス）
呪術師について詳しく知りたい？
Yeah, how do you avoid curses?
そう 呪いって
どうやったら防げるんだ
There isn't a way.
そんな方法はないのよ
Huh?
Once a curse is activated,
I suppose there isn't any way to undo it.
一度発動した呪術を解呪(かいじゅ)する方法は
存在しないかしら
Once it's activated, that's it.
発動したが最後
それが呪術なのよ
That's what curses are.
It's actually possible to nullify
instant death resistances?
即死耐性無効化とか ありかよ
However, before they're activated,
curses are just simple spells.
ただし―
発動前の呪術はただの術式だから
ベティーなら 解除は簡単なのよ
Before that, I could easily undo them.
The scent of the witch...
魔女の残り香
That reminds me, Rem mentioned that too.
そういや
レムもそんなこと言ってたな
Who is this witch?
魔女って何だ
Are witches related to shamans somehow?
ひょっとして 呪術師の
仲間だったりするのか
I suppose there's only one person in the world
the word "witch" ever refers to.
この世界で 魔女という
言葉が示すのは―
たった１人の存在だけかしら
The Witch of Envy?
嫉妬の魔女か
Exactly. The Witch of Envy, Satella.
それなのよ
嫉妬の魔女 サテラ
Long ago, she devoured the other six witches
who bore the names of the remaining deadly sins,
かつて存在した 大罪の名を冠する
６人の魔女を全て食らい―
and drained half the world dry.
I suppose she's the worst of the worst.
世界の半分を飲み干した
最悪の災厄なのかしら
Legends say that she was starved for love.
いわく 彼女は愛を欲していた
Legends say that she doesn't
understand human language.
いわく 彼女には
人の言葉が通じない
Legends say that her body never
withers, weakens, or dies.
いわく その身は永遠に朽ちず
衰えず 果てることがない
Legends say that, though she was sealed by
the powers of a dragon, a hero, and a sage,
いわく 竜と英雄と
賢者の力をもって―
封印させられしも
その身を滅ぼすこと かなわず
they were unable to destroy her flesh.
Legends say that her body is
that of a silver-haired half-elf.
いわく―
その身は 銀髪の
ハーフエルフであった
I'm...
私は… サテラ
Satella.
What would it take to make someone
steal the Witch of Envy's name?
（スバル）
嫉妬の魔女の名前をかたるのって
どんな時だろうな
Oh, I guess "steal" makes
the person sound bad.
あっ いや… かたるっつうと
人聞き悪いな
嫉妬の魔女の名前を
借りる時… のほうがいいか
I should say to make someone
"borrow" the Witch of Envy's name.
Either way, I suppose they
must have no fear of death.
なんにせよ
命知らずなことかしら
魔女の名前をかたるなんて―
An individual who would steal her name
can be considered nothing short of insane.
頭がおかしいとしか
言いようがないのよ
I see. It all makes sense now.
そうか それで…
Huh?
If people just saw her as a crazy freak,
おかしな奴だって
不気味がらせれば―
they wouldn't get dragged
into this royal selection mess.
王選絡みのいざこざに
巻き込まずに済むもんな
I suppose you could clarify.
何の話かしら
Don't worry about it.
何でもねえ
グッドモーニーン！
今日も晴天 洗濯物に絶好調！
Good morning!
It's another sunny day,
perfect for drying laundry!
ハピネスな１日にしようぜ！
Let's make this a happiness-filled day!
Now, victory!
はい ビクトリー！
Victory!
ビクトリー！
You're so energetic again this morning.
今日も朝から ホント元気よね
（スバル）
おう 今日も今日とて―
Yep! Even as I'm ordered around
and whipped by the maid sisters,
メイド姉妹に あれこれ指図
教育されつつも―
I'll enjoy my servant's life
to the fullest again!
使用人ライフ 満喫するぜ
But when that lifestyle wears me out,
けど そんな生活に
疲れきったら―
I'll come rest my head in your lap,
エミリアたんのひざに
飛び込みにいくから―
so save it for me, okay?
ちゃんと空けておいてね
顔とか洗ってるとこ見ると
マジ猫だなー
When you wash your face like that,
you really do look like a cat!
What, so spirits get sleepy and stuff too?
精霊とかも
やっぱ眠くなったりすんの？
寝坊したりする？
Do they oversleep?
Don't you people get sleepy
when you're fatigued too?
（パック）
君たちも 疲労がたまると
眠くなるでしょう？
精霊も 活動の源の
マナが減少すると―
When a spirits' mana, the source
of their energy, is depleted,
they experience something similar.
まあ 似たようなことになるよ…
Did you two stay up all night or what?
２人して夜更かしさんとか―
どうせ夜遅くまで―
I bet you were up late talking
about who you like, right?
好きな子の話とかで
盛り上がってたんだろ
Let me in on the fun!
俺も混ぜろよ
えっ 俺の好きな子？
それはね 恥ずかしいんだけど…
Say what?
Who I like? It's embarrassing to say, but—
The one I like is Puck,
and the one Puck likes is me.
私が好きなのはパックで
パックが好きなのは 私
There. That conversation's over.
はい お話おしまい
Your love is mutual!?
Then where do I fit in?
相思相愛？ 俺の割り込む余地は？
Nowhere.
ないとも
Lia's head-over-heels for my charms.
僕の魅力に
リアはメロメロだよ
You aren't a bad guy,
スバルも悪い男じゃないけど
僕と比べりゃ形無しだ
but compared to me,
you've got nothing.
素直にリアは諦めて…
You should give up on Lia and—
Don't get carried away, you two.
２人とも調子乗らないの！
Keep this up and I'll get mad!
そんなことだと
私も怒るんだからね
Ow! Ow! You already are!
You already are mad!
（スバル･パック）
痛い痛い 怒ってる怒ってる
Whoa, look at the time!
（スバル）おーっと
I should get going, lest I incur
the wrath of the maid sisters.
そろそろ行かねえと
メイド姉妹に怒られる
Bye.
ん？ どうしたの？
浮かない顔してるね
What's wrong? You don't look too happy.
How do I say it?
I feel sort of uneasy, I guess.
何だかこう… もやもやしてるの
うまく言葉にできないんだけど
It's hard to put into words.
まあ リアが戸惑うのも
無理はないよ
Well, I can't blame you for being confused.
少しばかり
困ったことになってるからね
This has gotten to be a bit of a problem.
Don't worry! Don't worry!
Forget about it! It's fine!
ドンマイドンマイ
気にすんな 大丈夫だ
A problem?
困ったこと？
Relax!
安心しろ 迅速な片づけで―
I'll clean this up real fast!
Don't want anyone getting hurt!
負傷者なんて
１人も出させやしないぜ
Subaru's mind is really mixed up.
スバルの心
だいぶごちゃごちゃしてる
外見と中身がぐちゃぐちゃだ
The inside and outside are all confused.
その心がけは
立派だと思いますけど―
I do think that is an admirable attitude,
but you were the one who knocked it over.
花瓶を落としたのも
スバルくんでしょ
替えの花瓶を
持ってきますから
I shall fetch a replacement—
No, that's okay!
（スバル）
いいや 大丈夫！ 花瓶も
花の手入れも俺がやるから
I'll take care of the vase and flowers!
Just focus on your own work!
先輩は自分の仕事してて
If he keeps this up,
he'll wear himself out before long.
（パック）あのままじゃ
そう遠くないうちに
すり切れちゃうんじゃないかな
ああ ひと仕事終えると
気持ちいいもんだな レムりん
It feels great to finish a job, huh, Rem-rin?
It was work you created
and took care of on your own, though.
自分で増やして
自分で片づけた お仕事でしたけど
いつの間に花瓶の場所なんて
聞いたんですか
When did you learn
where the vases are kept?
（スバル）おいっ…
（レム）姉様に
Did my sister...
Yeah, that's right! Your sister told me!
おっ おお そう 姉様に
Since she knows me, she said,
"You're bound to break a vase eventually.
俺のことだから―
きっと花瓶を割る機会が
あるに違いないわ―
I'll tell you where the extra vases are,
so you'll be prepared when it happens."
その時のために 花瓶の場所だけは
ちゃーんと教えておくわね
ってな アハ ハハハ…
スバルくん…
Subaru-kun...
Whoa, look at the time!
おおっと ラムちーに頼まれてる
仕事があったの忘れてた
I forgot Ram-chi asked me
to do some work for her!
I'll be done in no time,
so if you'll excuse me.
急いでそれ片づけてくるから
ちょっとごめんな
まったあっとでー
すぐ合流すっからー
Later! I'll come find you soon!
I feel sick...
（スバル）気持ち悪い
Don't you think my knife technique
has come a long way in only a day?
俺の包丁さばきってば―
たった１日で
かなり洗練されてねえ？
I think my talent has awakened!
才能が開花したんじゃない？
I feel sick. I feel sick. I feel sick!
（スバル）
気持ち悪い 気持ち悪い 気持ち悪い
Rem-rin, check out my aptitude,
which enables such detailed crafting!
この繊細な細工を可能とする技量
A miracle must be residing
in my fingertips right now!
今 俺の指先には
まさしく奇跡が宿っている
Illusion!
イリュージョン！
I feel sick... I feel sick... I feel sick...
（スバル）
気持ち悪い 気持ち悪い 気持ち悪い
I feel sick... I feel sick. I feel sick!
Honestly, Emilia-tan!
Every time we meet, you stir my heart!
エミリアたんてば 会うたび
俺の心をかき乱すなあ
You're such a sinful girl! You're guilty!
マジ 罪作りすぎて
ギルティだよ
I should be better able to laugh.
（スバル）
もっと上手に笑えるはずだ
もっとうまく笑わせられるはずだ
I should be better able to make them laugh.
Failure isn't an option this time.
今度は失敗できない
１秒だってムダにはできない
I can't waste a single second.
I have to throw myself into my work
and produce results, or else...
目の前の仕事に全力でぶつかって
ちゃんと成果 出さねえと
Oh, Ram-chi! I wasn't slacking!
I'll finish all my work!
おおっと ラムちー
サボりじゃねえよ
ちゃんとお仕事
やり遂げますとも
You can just kick back in your room
and take a siesta while I—
先輩はふんぞり返って―
部屋でステイしながら
シエスタしててもいいぐらい…
Damn, I look so lame.
（スバル）
ああ クソかっこ悪(わり)い…
You don't have time to spend whining.
弱音なんて
吐いてる暇があんのかよ
You idiot.
バカ野郎
（エミリア）スバル
（スバル）あっ
Subaru.
Emilia-tan!
エミリアたん
Subaru, come with me.
（エミリア）
スバル ちょっときて
Uh-oh! A personal request from Emilia-tan?
おおっと エミリアたんから
ご指名とは―
How rare! How joyous! How embarrassing!
うれし 恥ずかし 珍しーっ
Just say the word!
Your wish is my command!
何でも言って 何でも命じて
For you, I'd dive into fire,
water, the loot house, anywhere!
君のためなら たとえ火の中水の中
盗品蔵にだって潜っちゃう
Subaru...
スバル
Hey, come on!
The Emilia-tan I know would say...
おいおい 俺の知ってる
エミリアたんなら ここは―
Wait! Are you a fake?
は！ まさか偽物？
でも でも―
But could anyone else look so gorgeous
that I can barely resist my urge to hug her?
こんなかわいくて抱きしめたくなる
美少女っぷりを―
他人が再現できるものなのか？
All right.
よし
Subaru, come here.
スバル きなさい
Wha—
Just come.
（エミリア）いいから
じゃ ここに座って
Okay, sit here.
Can't I sit on the bed or a chair?
Why the floor?
座るなら ベッドでも
イスでもよくね？
何で わざわざ床に
Just sit!
（エミリア）いいから座るの
（スバル）
ああ はい 喜んで！
Yes, ma'am! With pleasure!
（エミリア）特別… だからね
Just this once, all right?
（エミリア）
ちょっと位置が悪い
それに ん… チクチクする
Your position is a little weird.
And... it tickles.
ひざ枕
You're letting me rest in your lap?
Don't say it aloud! It's embarrassing!
恥ずかしいから
はっきり言わないの
And no looking up here.
あと こっち見るのも禁止
Close your eyes.
目 つむってて
You're adorable when you're embarrassed, but...
恥じらうエミリアたんも
最高だけど―
What's this about anyway?
そもそも これってどういう状況
When did I do something
worthy of this kind of reward?
俺 いつの間にご褒美
もらえるような手柄立てたっけ？
You don't have to put on
that weird tough act now.
そういう変な強がり―
今はしなくていいの
言ったでしょ スバル
疲れきったらひざ枕してって
Didn't you tell me to lend you my lap
when you were exhausted?
いつもってわけにはいかないけど
今日は特別
I can't do this all the time,
but today is special.
Special? It's only my second day on the job.
特別って まだ２日目ですよ？
それで疲労困ぱいとか
俺 虚弱体質すぎるでしょ
What kind of weakling would I be
if I'm already completely worn out?
It's plain to see that you're overwhelmed.
打ちのめされてるの
見てれば分かるもん
You won't tell me what's
really going on, will you?
詳しい事情は
きっと話してくれないんでしょ
こんなことで 楽になるだなんて
思わないけど―
I can't imagine this will
make things any easier,
こんなことしか できないから
but this is all I can do.
アッハハ…
Emilia-tan, come on now...
エミリアたんでば そんな…
Are you tired?
疲れてる？
Not even a little bit. I'm totally fine.
（スバル）
まだまだ 全然平気だし
困ってる？
Are you troubled?
If you're this nice to me,
I'm gonna fall in love with you.
優しくされると… ほら
ほれちゃうぜ
そうやって また―
When you... I mean, like that...
そんな…
大変―
It's been rough, hasn't it?
だったね
（スバル）大変… だった
It's been rough.
It was so painful.
すげえつらかった
すげえ怖かった
I was so scared.
I was so sad.
めちゃくちゃ悲しかった
It hurt so much I thought I'd die.
死ぬかと思うくらい
痛かったんだよ
I know.
I tried so hard.
俺 頑張ったんだよ
頑張ってたんだよ！
So damn hard!
I was so desperate.
必死だった　必死でいろいろ―
So desperate to make everything right!
全部よくしようって
頑張ったんだよ
It's the truth.
ホントだ　ホントのホントに―
I've seriously never put so much effort
into anything in my entire life!
今まで―
こんなに頑張ったことなんて
なかったぐらい
I know, let it all out.
うん 分かってる
Because I loved this place.
好きだったからさ この場所が
大事だと思えてたからさ
この場所が　だから―
Because it was so important to me!
I was so desperate to get it back.
取り戻したいって
必死だったんだよ
怖かったよ
すげえ怖かったよ
I was scared. I was so scared!
I never want to be looked
at like that ever again!
また あの目で見られたらって―
そう思う自分が
イヤでイヤでしかたなかったよ
And I hated myself so much
for feeling that way!
Subaru-kun?
（ラム）スバルくん
（ラム）
スバルくんは寝ているだけですか
Is he simply asleep?
Yes.
（エミリア）そう　フフ…
He looks like a child, doesn't he?
ほら 子供みたいでしょう
今日はスバルくんに これ以上の
仕事はできそうにありませんね
It appears Subaru-kun cannot
do any more work today.
そうね 今日はお休み
Yes, he's done for today.
働き始めて２日で
休んじゃうなんて―
What a bad boy. It's only his second day of work,
yet he's already taking a day off.
すごーく悪い子
When he feels better, you can punish him.
元気になったら
お仕置きしてあげてね
Seeing him like this, I almost don't want to.
こうして見てると
その気も失せますね
Yeah.
I shall inform my sister that Subaru-kun
will be useless for the rest of the day.
（ラム）
姉様にスバルくんが
今日は役立たずだと伝えておきます
Rem.
（エミリア）レム
（レム）ん？
Subaru is a good person.
スバルはいい子よ
Did I really just bawl all
over the girl I love
（スバル）
意中の女の子相手に
超泣きわめいて―
and then fall asleep bathing
in my own tears and snot?
涙と鼻水で顔面ぐちゃぐちゃにして
眠りこける
What kind of shame play is that!?
I'm a lost cause! Totally hopeless!
どんな羞恥プレイだよ
ダメだ俺 すげえダメだ
I suppose that's all you have to say
after bursting in here late at night?
夜遅く上がり込んで
言い出す内容がそれかしら
Don't be like that, Lil' Bea!
We're tight, aren't we?
（スバル）
そう言うなよ ベア子
俺とお前の仲じゃんかよ
I suppose you have some
strange idea about our—
ベティーとお前にどんな関係…
Wait, what did you just call me?
待つのよ
今 何て呼んだかしら
Oh, "Lil' Bea"?
ああ ベア子な
I think pet names are indispensable
in showing affection.
俺は親近感の表現に
愛称は欠かせないと思うんだ
So I'm gonna call you Lil' Bea.
だから 俺は
お前をベア子と呼ぶよ
That's the best proof of my
affection that I can give.
それが お前にできる
俺の精一杯の親愛の証だ
What sort of obtrusive
display of goodwill is that?
何かしら
その押しつけがましい善意
Disgusting doesn't begin to describe that!
It's completely revolting!
気持ち悪いというより
胸くそ悪いのよ フン
Don't be so cold, Lil' Bea.
（スバル）
つれないこと言うなよ ベア子
実は―
The thing is...
切羽詰まって八方塞がりだ
I'm backed into a corner here.
Honestly, I want your help
with the curses I asked about.
ぶっちゃけ お前の手が借りたい
呪いの件だ
I suppose I already let you know that,
once activated, curses can't be undone.
発動した呪術は解呪できないと
言ったはずかしら
Yeah, you did.
確かに それは聞いた
But is it possible to detect curses
before they're activated?
なら 呪いが発動する前に
術式に気づくことはできないか？
It's perfectly possible to discover curses
before they're activated.
発動する前の術式なら
見つけることはできるのよ
How are curses placed?
呪いってどうやってかけるんだ
呪術には 絶対に外せない
ルールが存在するかしら
I suppose there's a single rule that
cannot be broken when casting curses.
A rule that can't be broken?
外せないルール？
呪術を行う対象との接触
これが必須条件なのよ
You must be in physical
contact with your target.
That is the prerequisite.
Other than those in this mansion,
誰かと接触したっていや―
I've only touched the villagers
at the base of the mountain.
屋敷のメンツを除いたら
ふもとの村しかねえ
So I was cursed in the village,
村で呪いの術式をうけ
その夜に屋敷で発動―
it activated in the mansion that night,
and then I died?
死に至るってパターンか
だったら 前回レムが―
That would explain why
the shaman got Rem last time.
呪術師の手にかかったのも
納得できる
俺が村に行かなかったから
狙いがレムへとずれたんだ
I didn't go to the village,
so she ended up being the target.
It fits. It all fits now!
つながる　全部つながった
I've finally found a lead!
ついに尻尾つかんだぜ
Holy crap!
チクショウ
I suppose that's one attitude to take
toward someone you asked for help.
人に協力を求めておいて
その態度はどうなのかしら
If you found it helpful, I believe there's
something you should be saying.
今の話が役立ったなら
言うべきことがあると思うのよ
ああ そうだな！
Yeah, that's right!
You saved me!
助かった！ お前のおかげで
光が見えたぜ
Thanks to you, I can see the light!
Lil' Bea, I love you!
ベア子 愛してる
Let me—
I suppose I want down!
下ろすかしら！
Dorowazu!
（スバル）ドロワズッ
ってなわけで
まあ いろいろあったが―
And so, a lot's happened,
but today is a fresh start! I'm a new me!
今日からは心機一転
New 俺でいくぜ！
It was the lap pillow, right?
ひざ枕ですね
It was the lap pillow.
ひざ枕だわね
Huh?
Wait, you guys knew?
ひょっとして みんな知ってんの？
Subaru, good morning.
スバル おはよう
Emilia-tan?
エミリアたん
Um, this is kind of embarrassing.
えっと… 何だか
気恥ずかしいわね
Are you feeling okay?
体調とか 大丈夫？
I wasn't so sure till I heard
your voice just now, but...
今 エミリアたんの声
聞くまで危なかったけど
もう大丈夫
I'm okay now.
So, um, listen...
その… 何だ―
I'm sorr—
いろいろと ごめ…
I mean, thanks for everything.
いや いろいろとありがとう
いいえ
You're very welcome.
どういたしまして
Well, shall we start on this
morning's work, Subaru-kun?
（レム）
では そろそろ朝の仕事に
入りましょうか スバルくん
We need to begin our morning duties.
（ラム）そろそろ
朝のお勤めを始めなきゃね
Before that, I have a favor to ask.
その前に お願いがあるんだけど
A lap pillow, right?
（レム）ひざ枕ですね
It's a lap pillow.
ひざ枕だわね
I'm not that unscrupulous!
（スバル）
そんな節操無しじゃねえよ
Actually, I want to go check out the village.
実は村に行ってみたいんだ
近くにあるだろ？
It's not far, right?
Do we have any plans to shop for anything?
買いだしの予定とか ないかな？
確か 香辛料が心もとないので―
If I recall, we are low on seasonings,
明日にでも村に行こうと
思っていましたけど
so I was thinking of going to
the village tomorrow.
Then why don't we go today instead?
じゃあ その予定ずらして
今日とかどうよ
無くなりそうなら
早いに越したことないし
If we're running low,
it never hurts to restock sooner!
いいんじゃないの それくらい
I don't see a problem with that.
姉様
Sister?
You do need to go shopping,
and we have no urgent duties.
買いだしには行かなきゃ
ならないのだし―
急な用事もない
And Balse will be there to carry everything.
バルスという
荷物運びもいることだし
If you say so, Sister.
（レム）
姉様がそう言うのなら
All right!
（スバル）よっしゃー！
But I'm going with you.
ただし ラムも一緒に行くわ
You'll have a pretty flower
on each arm, Balse.
両手に花というやつよ バルス
Huh?
え？ その花―
Uh, I just hope those
flowers aren't poisonous.
毒とか
持ってないといいですね
I Cried, Criedmy  Lungs Out,
and  Stopped Crying